<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<component>
    <name>GetStatistics</name>
    <!--<version>1.0</version>-->
    <doc>
    This component predicts sites for a given WM on given sequences (aligned or not aligned) and relates the predictions to chip-seq signal.
    Input files are sequences or alignments (usually) from the coordinates given by PeakMerger (non refined peaks), region coverage files over these sequences, a weight matrix and the peakstats file of SelectPeaksMM.
    The peakstats file contains the peaks selected inside the non refined peaks from PeakMerger and corresonding statistics (height, RMSD (quality), mu, sigma).
    The following plots get produced:
        -Histogram of distance of predicted site (posterior cut-off of 0.2) to nearest peak center. Also scatter of this distance versus site posterior.
        -Scatter and box-violin-plots of peak height and peak quality (from peakstats file) versus post 
    Several WMs and their corresponding quality scores (as given by RunMotevo) can be given as input. The best scoring WM is then used for predictions. Also a countour plot is generated that plots the ratio of true/untrue regions that you would get upon applyng a certain length and height cut-off. This is for validation or justification of the applied length and height cut-off.
    </doc>
    <author email="severin.berger@stud.unibas.ch">Severin</author>
    <launcher type="python">
        <argument name="file" value="GetStatistics.py" />
    </launcher>
    <requires>URL="http://www.python.org/not" type="manual">python</requires>
    <inputs>
        <input name="peakstats" type="BinaryFile">
            <doc>File conating all the statistics of all peaks (zscore, rmsd, posterior). Output file of GetPeakPosteriors component.</doc>
        </input>
        <input name="TFBSstats" type="BinaryFile">
            <doc>File containing binding sites and the coverage at the site. Output file of GetPeakPosteriors component.</doc>
        </input>
        <input name="RegCov_dir" type="BinaryFolder">
            <doc>Directory containing the files with all region coverage profiles.</doc>
        </input>
    </inputs>
    <outputs>
        <output name="log_file" type="BinaryFile">
            <doc>Log file.</doc>
        </output>
        <output name="TFBS_peakcenter_dist_hist" type="PDF">
            <doc>Histogram of distances between a TFBS (above minposterior) and the center of it's nearest peak.</doc>
        </output>
        <output name="TFBS_post_peakcenter_dist_scatter" type="PDF">
            <doc>Scatter plot of distance of TFBS to it's nearest peakcenter versus TFBS posterior.</doc>
        </output>
        <output name="zscore_post_scatter" type="PDF">
            <doc>
            Scatter plot of peak z-score versus peak posterior.
            Posterior of a peak is the sum of all posteriors under the peak (2*fraglen around peakcenter).
            </doc>
        </output>
        <output name="quality_post_scatter" type="PDF">
            <doc>
            Scatter plot of peak quality (RMSD) versus peak posterior.
            Posterior of a peak is the sum of all posteriors under the peak (2*fraglen around peakcenter).
            </doc>
        </output>
        <output name="zscore_post_violin" type="PDF">
            <doc>
            Violin- and boxplots of peak posterior distributions of peaks stratified by peak z-score.
            Posterior of a peak is the sum of all posteriors under the peak (2*fraglen around peakcenter).                                                                                                                             
            </doc>
        </output>
        <output name="quality_post_violin" type="PDF">
            <doc>
            Violin- and boxplots of peak posterior distributions of peaks stratified by peak quality.
            Posterior of a peak is the sum of all posteriors under the peak (2*fraglen around peakcenter).                                                                                                                             
            </doc>
        </output>
        <output name="TFBSheight_TFBSpost_scatter" type="PDF">
            <doc>Scatter plot of TFBS posterior versus the height/coverage right at the TFBS position.</doc>
        </output>
        <output name="post_hist" type="PDF">
            <doc>histogram of peak posteriors.</doc>
        </output>
        <output name="post_cumulative" type="PDF">
            <doc>Cumulative distribution of peak posteriors.</doc>
        </output>
        <output name="coverage_histograms" type="PDF">
            <doc>Histogram of coverage at sites and histogram of bp region coverage</doc>
        </output>
    </outputs>
    <parameters>
        <parameter name="minposterior" type="float" default="0.2">
            <doc>Posterior cut-off to call site true.</doc>
        </parameter>
    </parameters>
</component>
