<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<component>
    <name>ReduceWMs</name>
    <!--<version>1.0</version>-->
    <doc>
      This component tries to narrow down the candidate WM set (from phylogibbs, from motevo refinement, given WMs).
      It sorts WMs by a given score (AUC if you give log_file of WMQuality component or likelihood of sequences if you given log_file of ComputeLikelihood component).
      Then it goes down the list, keeping just WMs that do not look very similar.
      Similarity of two WMs is defined by the convolution at their optimal relative position. Similarity score is computed to a distance.
      From WMs that have smaller distance to each other than given distance_cutoff just the one WM with highest AUC or likelihood score resp. is given out. 
      The purpose of this is to have less candidate WMs to do the downstream analysis.
    </doc>
    <launcher type="python">
        <argument name="file" value="ReduceWMs.py" />
    </launcher>
    <requires>URL="http://www.python.org/not" type="manual">python</requires>
    <inputs>
        <input name="infile" type="BinaryFile">
            <doc>File containing scores for all candidate WMs. It's either the log_file of WMQuality or ComputeLikelihood</doc>
        </input>
        <input name="keepWM" type="BinaryFile" optional="true">
            <doc>One WM that should be included in the out port WMdir in any case. This WM should also be in infile, though. Otherwise problems will arise later.</doc>
        </input>
    </inputs>
    <outputs>
        <output name="WMdir" type="BinaryFolder">
            <doc>Directory containing the final candidate WMs.</doc>
        </output>
        <output name="log_file" type="BinaryFile">
            <doc>Contains the final candidate WMs (original path and new name).</doc>
        </output>
    </outputs>
    <parameters>
        <parameter name="distance_cutoff" type="float" default="0.1">
            <doc>Distance is defined as d = 1 - (2*S_ij)/(S_ii+S_jj), where S_ij is similarity score between WM_i and WM_j, S_ii and S_jj are similarity scores from a WM to itself.</doc>
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="score_cutoff" type="float" default="0.0">
            <doc>WMs with lower score (usually log-likelihood, or AUC) than this are not given out.</doc>
        </parameter>
    </parameters>
</component>
