<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<component>
    <name>RunMotevo</name>
    <!--<version>1.0</version>-->
    <doc>
    This component runs motevo for weight matrix refinement. 
    It also produces a positive predictive value vs. sensitivity plot and the logo of the refined weight matrix.
    For this it takes two halfs of the alignments (refined regions), the old WM and shuffled peaks as input. 
    For the ppv - sensitivity analysis it predicts binding sites one the odd half and on the shuffledPeaks with the old WM.
    Then WM is refined with even half and predictions are computed again. 
    Curve for both analyses are then computed by calling a peak a true site if summed transcription factor binding sites posteriors on a certain region are greater than a cut-off.
    The cut-off is varied from 0 up to highest scoring region to get this plot.  
    </doc>
    <launcher type="python">
        <argument name="file" value="RunMotevo.py" />
    </launcher>
    <requires>URL="http://www.python.org/not" type="manual">python</requires>
    <inputs>
        <input name="odd_file" type="BinaryFile">
            <doc>Half of alignments (from Splitalignments) used to predict sites on.</doc>
        </input>
        <input name="even_file" type="BinaryFile">
            <doc>Even half of Alignments from SplitAlignments. Used for WM refinement.</doc>
        </input>
        <input name="WM" type="BinaryFile">
            <doc>Wm to refine: either old existing one or the one found by PhyloGibbs.</doc>
        </input>
        <input name="shuffledPeaks" type="BinaryFile">
            <doc>Shuffled Peaks to predict sites on. From ShufflePeaks component.</doc>
        </input>
        <input name="WM2" type="BinaryFile" optional="true">
            <doc>If this one is defined, a ROC plot is drawn for this (WM2) together with WM. If not defined, WM is refined (motevo) and ROC plot thereof is drawn.</doc>
        </input>
        <input name="UFEmodel" type="BinaryFile" optional="true">
            <doc>File containing the UFE model. Only optional when ran without alignments.</doc>
        </input>
        <input name="BaseFrequencies" type="BinaryFile" optional="true">
            <doc>File from BuildUFEmodel component containing the frequencies of A/t and G/C. Only optional when ran without alignments.</doc>
        </input>
    </inputs>
    <outputs>
        <output name="intermediate" type="BinaryFolder">
            <doc>Tracking output file.</doc>
        </output>
        <output name="refWM" type="BinaryFile">
            <doc>This is the refined weight matrix.</doc>
        </output>
        <output name="sens_ppv" type="PDF">
            <doc>Sensitivity positive predictive value plot.</doc>
        </output>
        <output name="Logo" type="PDF">
            <doc>Logo of the refined weight matrix.</doc>
        </output>
        <output name="nonref_WM_Quality" type="BinaryFile">
            <doc>Quality value for non-refined weight matrix based on specificty sensitivity performance.</doc>
        </output>
        <output name="ref_WM_Quality" type="BinaryFile">
            <doc>Quality value for refined weight matrix based on specificty sensitivity performance.</doc>
        </output>
    </outputs>
    <parameters>
        <parameter name="genome" type="string" default="">
            <doc>genome: hg19, mm9 ...</doc>
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="mylogo_path" type="string" default="">
            <doc>Path to mylogo logo creation script.</doc>
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="motevo_path" type="string" default="">
            <doc>Path to motevo executable.</doc>
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="minpostwm" type="float" default="0.25">
            <doc>Minimal posterior of sites to be included for WM refinement.</doc>
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="wmdiff" type="float" default="0.0075">
            <doc>Maximal difference between old and refined WM. Convergence criterion. A smaller number would be better, but then it too often doesn't converge (annoying for automation).</doc>
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="aligned" type="boolean" default="true">
            <doc>Whether input files (even and odd) are aligned or not (relevant for TFBS predictions).</doc>
        </parameter>
    </parameters>
 </component>
