<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<component>
    <name>RegionCoverage</name>
    <!--<version>1.0</version>-->
    <doc>
    This component computes the read coverage over a region. It accounts for read weights.
    It takes shifted bedweight files (output from FragmentLength component) and 500 top scoring regions from PeakMerger as input.
    First, reads are set to fragment length. Fragment length is read from the FragmentLength component's output.
    With intersectBed from bedtools it finds intersecting reads for each region. 
    Then it computes bp resolved coverage: For each bp in a region, how many reads overlap it (averaged over replicates). 
    The output is 500 files (one per region) with coverage per bp.
    </doc>
    <author email="severin.berger@stud.unibas.ch">Severin</author>
    <launcher type="python">
        <argument name="file" value="RegionCoverage.py" />
    </launcher>
    <requires>URL="http://www.python.org/not" type="manual">python</requires>
    <inputs>
        <input name="regions" type="BinaryFile">
            <doc>Outfile of PeakMerger.</doc>
        </input>
    </inputs>
    <outputs>
        <output name="intermediate" type="BinaryFolder">
            <doc>Contains intermediate steps output.</doc>
        </output>
        <output name="out_dir" type="BinaryFolder">
            <doc>Where to write the output to, contains 500 files with coverage per bp. One for each region.</doc>
        </output>
        <output name="log_file" type="BinaryFile">
            <doc>log file.</doc>
        </output>
    </outputs>
    <parameters>
        <parameter name="read_files" type="string" default="">
            <doc>string with space separated paths to shifted bedweight files with fragment length reads (output from FragmentLength, string is produced by network.and).</doc>
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="regionlength" type="int" default="-1">
            <doc>Integer that can be set to make all regions to an equal length of e.g. 2000 bp. Default is -1, which  means that regions lengths aren't adapted.</doc>
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="toFraglength" type="boolean" default="true">
            <doc>Here one can turn off that reads are extended to fragment length. Default is on.</doc>
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="BedToolsPath" type="string" default="/import/bc2/home/nimwegen/GROUP/bedtools">
            <doc>Path to directory containing bedtools suite executable.</doc>
        </parameter>
    </parameters>
</component>
